5  孝敬父母
3  不可妄言主之名
6  不可杀人
4  纪念安息日  尊为圣日
9  不可作假证
10  不可觊觎
8  不可偷窃
7  不可通奸
1  不可尊他神
2  不可制造偶像
美国恐怖故事  旅馆
第五季 第九集
女人的衰老与男人不同
Women age differently than men do.
男人的左心室
In a man, the left ventricle,
就是将鲜血泵入体内的一边随着年龄增长
the one that pumps red blood into the body, gets larger,
变大变厚
thicker as he gets older.
而女人的左心室则萎缩
In a woman, it shrinks.
我现在已经一百多岁了
I am now more than a century old.
我的心脏现在一定只有几克拉了
My heart must be just a few karats at this point.
里面能装下的东西很少
There is room there for very little,
所以里面仍装有的东西
so what still fits inside
对我来说尤为重要
means more to me than ever.
对我来说就是一切
It means everything.
这一百年的不死生命
The last 100 years of my immortal life
都是个谎言
have been a lie.
是控制的幻觉
The illusion of control.
事实上  我什么都没有控制过
In truth, I have controlled nothing.
罗多弗·瓦伦蒂诺
我身边都是蠢货  谄媚者
I have surrounded myself with fools and flatterers,
相信那些不值得信任之人
put my trust in those who could not be trusted.
联合车站
我猜
I have a sneaking suspicion
你们恐怕要错过火车了
you're going to miss your train.
外患
Enemies without.
内鬼
Enemies within.
该建设点新东西了
It is time to construct something new.
持久的东西
Something durable.
用铁  石  和钢坚固铸就
With fortifications of iron, stone and steel.
我绝不要被支配
I will not be ruled.
我绝不要被控制
I will not be managed.
我们把这些都撤掉
We move all of this.
在那边加个舞池
I pop in a dance floor over there.
我让凯文飞过来主持音乐
I'll fly in Calvin to do the music.
我们别粗俗地摆排场了
Let's not have some big vulgar display.
我更希望我们办个简单私密的仪式
I'd rather we just do something simple and intimate.
我只需要你  地方执法官
All I need is you, a justice of the peace,
让拉科伦做戒童
Lachlan to bear the rings,
再摆上一堆百合
and sprays of lilies of the valley.
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
威尔·德雷克要结婚了
Will Drake is getting married.
这场婚礼必须是本季最盛大的活动
This wedding needs to be the event of the season.
相信我  我是表演家
Trust me, I'm a showman.
我就是做这个的
This is what I do.
我不是展品
Well, I'm no show pony.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我爱你  威尔
I love you, Will.
你需要我
You need me,
我让你复原了
I'm restorative,
但你让这世界
but you let the world
吸干了你的灵感
suck you dry of any inspiration,
而现在又想把他们再邀回来
and now you want to invite them back in.
我不能允许
I can't be a part of it.
要么是他们  要么是我
It's them or me.
当然是你
It's you.
永远是你
It's-it's always you.
如果你想办私密点  那就这样
If you want something intimate, then that's what it'll be.
这是你的婚礼
This is your wedding.
是我们的婚礼
It's our wedding.
你为我设计婚纱
You design my gown.
我会负责其他事宜
I'll take care of everything else.
我想那的确会很尴尬
I suppose it would be a little awkward
那么多狗仔队
with all that paparazzi around
而你偏巧又
and you being so...
不喜欢上镜
camera shy, as it were.
周三早上把花送来
Have the flowers delivered by Wednesday morning.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
是吧
Right?
贱人  你真觉得
Bitch, do you honestly think
你做了那种事
I would lift a finger to help you with your wedding
我还会帮你准备婚礼吗
after what you did?
特里斯坦才没爱过你
Tristan never loved you.
他根本不会爱
He didn't know how to love.
你根本不了解他
You didn't know him...
一点不了解
at all.
他爱过我的
He did love me.
你或许夺走了他
You may have taken him away,
但这你休想夺走
But I will not let you take that.
自己去买花吧
Buy your own damn flowers.
我的馈赠背叛了我
My largess betrays me.
那些接受我慷慨馈赠之人
Those to whom I have given much
却对我报以怨恨和不知感恩
repay me only with resentment and ingratitude.
安全只有在自己身上能找到
Security can be found only by looking into oneself.
其他人只会把事情搞砸
Others only make a mess of things.
一具流浪汉的尸体
The body of a homeless man,
昨晚在工业城被发现
who appears to have been exsanguinated,
似乎被人放干了血
was found in the city of industry last night.
尚不知道此人的血是怎样被放干
No word on how the man's blood was drained,
或者此事是否与这几周来发生在市内的
or if this might be related to a series of similar murders
流浪汉身亡  尸体被放干血
一系列相似的杀人案相关
that have taken place in the city over the past few weeks.
警方在搜索一群
Police are searching for a small group of children
可能目睹了袭击的孩子
who may have witnessed the attack.
一个女人的忍耐也是有极限的
A woman can only be pushed so far.
我已经到极限了
And I'm right on the edge.
我累了
I'm weary.
喂
Hello.
受够了这世界令我失望
Weary of the world failing me.
我好像找到你的人了
Yeah, I think I found your boy.
受够了一直不停的失望
Weary of the steady drip, drip of disappointment.
我不要再被辜负了
I won't be disappointed again.
我可以进来吗
May I come in?
你得先吻吻我
Only if you kiss me first.
天呐
Oh, god.
我忘记你在我体内的感觉多棒了
I forgot how good you feel inside me.
天呐
Oh, god.
我为什么会让你离开我啊
Why did I ever let you leave me?
你没有让我离开
You didn't let me.
你把我赶走了
You threw me out.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
没错
That's right.
你该更积极争取的
You should have fought harder.
我想争取来着  但你赶在我之前把他杀了
Well, I was going to, but you killed him before I could.
保证我
Promise me...
今后只有我
from now on it's just me.
永远只有我
Forever.
一夫一妻吗  多诺万
Monogamy, Donovan?
是承诺
Commitment.
我们可以跟我们喜欢的人做我们喜欢的事
We can do what we want with whoever we want...
但你只能爱我
...but you love only me.
我发誓
I swear it.
但我不会犯同样的错误了
But I won't make the same mistakes again.
我要不止语言
It's going to require more than words.
我要行动
It requires actions.
你要什么都行  亲爱的
Whatever you want, baby.
很好
Good.
我周三要结婚了
I'm getting married on Wednesday.
什么
What?
放松  我周四就会是寡妇了
Relax. I'll be a widow by Thursday.
有钱的寡妇
A rich widow.
我想重新开始一切
I want to make a clean start of things.
清理我们生活的所有障碍
Clear away all the detritus of our lives.
太好了  我们先杀谁
Great, who should we kill first?
干掉你未婚夫之后
After your betrothed, I mean.
我们列个名单吧
Let's make a list.
抱歉
Sorry,
二逼大会在希尔顿酒店召开
douche bag convention is over at the Hilton.
我们有预定
We have a reservation.
用我的名字  斯特姆考克预定的
Under my name, Stormcock.
好吧
Okay.
那是...
Would that be a...
姓氏  还是全名  像麦当娜那样
Last name or the whole thing, like Madonna?
你有没有查到预约登记
Do you have the reservation or not?
就在这里
It's right here.
那么
So, uh,
你们打算在上面做什么
what are you guys planning on doing up there?
就是一般那些
Oh, nothing unusual.
异性性爱  口交
Straight sex, blow job.
我可能会舔她菊花
I'll probably rim her.
你休想把舌头伸进我菊花里
You're not sticking your tongue in my ass.
没什么比装逼的色情片女星更烦人的了
Nothing like a prude porn star.
等你们入住了
I'll bring up some extra towels
我会多送去几条毛巾
after you've settled in.
谢谢
Thank you.
我对黄片没什么意见
I've got nothing against pornography
如果拍得好的话
when it's done right.
我像其他人一样
I went and saw deep throat
去圣塔莫尼卡大道的皇家剧院
at the royal on Santa Monica Boulevard,
看了《深喉》
just like everybody else.
就连威廉·巴克利都去看了
Hell, even William Buckley went.
媒体人  作家
保守主义政治评论家
那是真正的演员拍的
That was shot with real actors,
在片场拍摄  有剧本
on sets, with a script.
如今  随便两个什么人都能拿个iPhone
Nowadays any couple of yahoos can take out their iphones
假装是色情片大导演
and pretend to be the Sydney Pollack of sex flicks.
因为互联网
And because of that world wide web,
他们还能大挣一笔
they can actually make a buck off of it.
他们很多人都来科泰兹旅馆
And plenty of them are picking the Hotel Cortez
制作他们的糟糕作品
to make their mess-terpieces.
过去  我承认  我还推波助澜
In the past, I'll admit it, I was an enabler.
我拿他们的钱  给他们把钥匙
I'd take the money and hand them a key
不去想楼上发生的事
and try not to think about what was happening upstairs.
但自从我转化后  我无法不去想
But ever since I was converted, I can't turn away.
我不想不去想
I don't want to.
这是个新的我
It's a new me.
我成了个女霸王
I'm becoming a goddamn Dirty Harriet.
黄片对人有伤害
Porn hurts people.
伤害那些以为自己也得那么上床的女孩
Hurts the girls who think they need to screw like that.
伤害那些以为女孩喜欢那样上床的男人
Hurts the guys who think girls want to screw like that.
我并不是刻板
I'm not uptight,
我只是不希望这种事再在我的旅馆里发生
I just don't want it going on in my hotel anymore.
多诺万会喜欢他坚强的新母亲的
Donovan will like his strong new mother.
我如今简直是全世界母亲的榜样了
Hell, I'm an example for mothers everywhere now.
我就说你太吵了
I told you you were being too loud.
我假装的时候总是喊得很响
I'm always loud when I'm faking it.
怎么回事
What the hell?
二逼
Douche bag.
天呐
Oh, god. ‭
求你  我不想死
Please, I don't want to die.
我不想
I don't want to...
你好  艾芮斯
Hello, Iris.
多诺  你怎么来了
Dono, what are you doing here?
我听说了你几周前
I mean, I heard what you did
对那些潮人做的事
to those hipsters a couple weeks ago,
还有你准备杀了女伯爵的孩子
about how you were ready to off the countess' kids,
但我以为那是谣传呢
but I thought it was just tall tales.
但你显然是变威风了
But you have Clearly come into your own.
都因为你
'cause of you.
听我说
But listen,
你在这儿不安全
it's not safe for you here.
出问题了
There's been a problem.
有人把巴塞洛缪放出去了
Someone let Bartholomew out of his room.
该死
Shit.
我差点失去了他
I nearly lost him.
我要知道究竟是谁干的
I demand to know who's responsible.
不是我啊
Well, wasn't me.
你要保护的那条性命
Is the life you're protecting
值得你为之送命吗
really worth losing your own?
或是你儿子的命
Or your son's?
多诺万跟那事无关
Donovan had nothing to do with it.
是拉蒙娜·罗耶尔
It was Ramona Royale.
我担心她会发现
I'm worried that she's gonna put it together
我们三个是串通好的
that the three of us are in cahoots.
我们需要B计划
We need a plan "B."
我早想好了
I'm way ahead of you.
女伯爵以为我又跟她和好了
The countess thinks I'm back with her.
这就是我来的原因
That's why I'm here.
她没有钩住你吧
Tell me she doesn't have her hooks in you.
没有  母亲
Not at all, mother.
听我说
Look...
淡定  低调
Just sit tight, keep quiet.
你知道的越少越好
The less you know, the better.
等我需要你时  我会告诉你的
And when I need you, I'll let you know.
有人吗  谁能报警
Hey, hello? Can somebody call the police?
不要
No, no...
我们太性感了  伙计
We are hot shit, buddy.
你居然要娶女人
I can't believe you're marrying a girl.
我就直说了
I'm gonna be blunt.
你父亲是双性恋
Your father is bisexual.
人们觉得那个词很肮脏
People think that word means something dirty,
但并不是的
but it doesn't.
意思是  我既喜欢男人也喜欢女人
It means I like men and I like women.
一样喜欢
Equally.
人们不理解
People don't understand,
就把我视为怪人
so they treat me like I'm weird.
或者像是我有所隐瞒
Or like I'm trying to hide something.
-或者...  -你只喜欢男人
- or that... - That you only like guys?
是啊  差不多
Yeah, something like that.
如果你走运
And if you're lucky,
你这辈子
once in your life
能碰上那么一个真正理解你的人
you find somebody who really understands you.
我本来没想到我能碰到那样的人
And I didn't think someone like that existed for me.
直到我遇到女伯爵
Until I met the Countess.
她就是真命天女
She's the one.
等你遇见了你的真命天女
And when you meet the one,
一定要把握好她
you hold on tight
不要放弃
and you never let go.
别娶她
Don't marry her.
她并不合适你
She's not the one for you.
不适合任何男人
For any man. ‭
抱歉  你是谁  你怎么进来的
Excuse me, who are you? How did you get in here?
那是爱弗斯女士  她在这儿工作
That's Ms. Evers. She works here. ‭
要我给你一把刀吗  德雷克先生
Would you like me to bring you a knife, Mr. Drake?
或许一把手枪
Perhaps a pistol?
还是你是那种
Or are you the type who would prefer
更喜欢跳楼的人
to hurl yourself out a window?
什么
Excuse me?
你显然是想自寻短见
Well, clearly you want to commit suicide.
否则你为什么会愿
Why else would you agree
娶那个毒妇
to marry that poisonous leech of a woman?
你太过分了
You are way out of line.
你如果娶女伯爵  你必死无疑
If you marry the Countess you will die.
你的儿子大概也会死
And your boy, too, probably.
快滚出去
Get the hell out of here.
你必须相信我  先生
You must believe me, sir.
一旦她把戒指带在你手上  就会吸干你的血
Once she puts the ring on your finger she will bleed you dry.
婚前协议可以保护我
I have a prenup to protect me from that.
快滚出去  你被解雇了
Get the hell out of here. You're fired.
我本来该结婚的
I was supposed to be married.
我爱他
I loved him.
但他选择去爱她
But he chose to love her instead.
我父亲总说要娶一个
My father always said to marry
朴素的女人  会少很多麻烦
a homely woman. Less trouble.
我不同意
I disagree.
我喜欢你  我依赖你
I adore you. I depend on you.
看我穿得这身西装
Look at the suit I'm wearing.
原本上面沾满了胆汁
It was covered in bile, literal bile,
我那天在卧铺车上捅死的男人身上的胆汁
from a pullman I knifed the other day.
而现在就好像从没脏过一样
It's like nothing was ever there.
你真是个天才
You're a genius.
但女伯爵就是上帝的完美产物
But the Countess is a creature from heaven.
时髦
Style,
优雅  美丽
grace, beauty.
你们有着不同的优点
It's not your fault you were graced with...
这不是你的错
different gifts.
每人会从她手底下逃脱
No one survives her.
请你离开
Please leave.
我再也不想在旅馆里见到你
I never want to see you in this hotel again.
不信算了
So be it.
那天很快就会到来
One day, very soon,
你会明白的
you will understand.
你只会收获痛苦
You will know nothing but pain, hmm?
而我会在那里等你
And I will be there.
你会向我寻求帮助和慈悲
And you will reach out to me for help and mercy,
那时我会面带笑容看着你死去
and in return I will watch you die with a smile on my face,
因为我知道等你一死
because I will know that once you are gone
我就有机会清理你身上穿得那套正装
I will get the chance to clean the blood and shit
上面的血渍和屎尿
out of that pretty formal wear of yours.
我只想证实一下  因为好像
I just wanted to confirm ‭everything because it looks like
有人想打开这面墙
someone just tried to open up this wall.
是的  而我告诉你现在关上它
Yes, and I'm telling you now to close it.
有了这扇防盗门  我就会把这间小屋
With a security door. I'm turning this entire wing
变成德雷克先生珍藏品的秘密储藏室
into a secure archive for Mr. Drake's previous collections.
它必须牢不可破
It needs to be impenetrable.
当然了  是为了安全考虑
For insurance purposes, of course.
如果我们先问过主人的意见会更好一些
I'd feel more comfortable if we checked with the owner first.
我们不要让他知道
We won't say anything to him.
这是个惊喜  是结婚礼物
It's a surprise. A wedding gift.
好日子是什么时候
When's the happy day?
希望明天前一切都能完工
I expect this all to be done by tomorrow.
可这要花上至少一周时间来整理这些东西
I mean, it's gonna take at least a week to order these parts.
你有一打吸顶式网络摄像头
You got a dozen ceiling-mounted IP cameras,
-还有生物识别扫描  -我对细节没兴趣
- you got Biometric... - Details don't interest me, boo.
结果才是最重要的
Results are the only thing that matters.
你的要求根本无法完成
What you're asking is impossible.
"想要实现这些不可能
"In order to attain the impossible,
必须勇于大胆尝试"
one must attempt the absurd."
米格尔·德·塞万提斯
Miguel De Cervantes.
他是你的装潢师吗
Is this your decorator?
我是她的匿名合伙人
I'm the silent partner.
这位女士对装修有其独到的见解  不是吗
The lady has an eye for improvements, does she not?
如我之前解释的
Well, as I was explaining,
有很多东西要搬
there's a lot of moving parts.
你被这些无关紧要的东西遮蔽了双眼
You are clouding your mind with the inconsequential.
其实很简单
It's quite simple.
这是一面承重墙
This is a load-bearing wall.
它足可以承受你附加在上面的
Abundantly strong enough for just about
任何钢筋
any steel you lug up here.
然后  就只需要几个铆钉就搞定了
After that, it's just a matter of a few rivets.
这方面我有着丰富的经验
I have extensive experience on this.
带上你的工具和你的工人
Gather your materials and your men
我领你们进去
and I will guide you through it.
-我尽力吧  -这就对了嘛
- I'll do what I can. - That's the spirit!
快一点  有很多事要做呢
Make haste! Much to accomplish!
不用劳烦你那漂亮的小脑袋  亲爱的
Don't you worry your pretty head, dear.
我一定会让你得偿所愿的
I'll see to it you get what you want.
你是不是疯了
Are you out of your goddamn mind?!
如果你不是早死了  我一定杀了你
I'd kill you if you weren't dead already.
你真让我恶心
You disgust me.
你还在为那个外国佬的事而生气啊
You're still upset about the dago.
你搞砸了  吉米
You screwed up, Jimmy.
你抢走了我最心爱的东西
You robbed me of the thing I loved the most.
现在我永远都不想再看见
And now I never want to see your pathetic,
你那可怜又可悲的脸了
miserable face ever again.
但我们有约定的
But we have an arrangement.
求你
Please.
共进晚餐是我在地狱般的地方里唯一的慰藉
Our dinners are my sole comfort in this stygian heap.
明天前  密室必须要修好
The chamber must be completed by tomorrow.
你要是敢跑  我会立马杀了你
‭You try to run, I will kill you so fast.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
有人教导我空手拜访客人是很无礼的
I was taught it was impolite to visit a friend empty-handed.
闭嘴
‭Shut up.
我知道你是哪种朋友了
I saw what kind of friend you were.
你是只可怕的娘们  多诺万
You're a scared little pussy, Donovan.
找不到你的种
Couldn't find your balls
因为它们被串成串挂在她的床柱上了
if they were dangling by a string on her bedpost.
我需要一个人帮我扳倒她  你永远不是
You could never be the kind of man I need to take her down.
你错了
You're wrong.
我有了新的动机
I've been newly motivated.
说说看
Tell me more.
我喜欢听被羞辱的故事
I love a good humiliation.
她又对你做了什么以前没做过的事了
What did she do to you that she hasn't already done?
她让我回去
She took me back.
是的
Yeah.
女伯爵说她错了
The Countess told me she made a mistake,
我才是她的最爱  永远的爱人
and I was the one. Forever.
我们像第一次时那样做爱
We made love like it was the first time.
但你并不相信她
But you didn't believe her.
我相信了
Oh, I did. I did.
我比之前更想拥有她
I wanted her even more than I did before.
因为我知道没有她的日子是什么样的
Because I knew what it felt like to live without her.
而那让我意识到
And that's-that's when I realized
我对她的渴望永远无法挥去
it was never going away-- my desperation for her.
有种永远无法满足的渴望
It's a horrible feeling to have a craving
真是太可怕了
that you could never satiate.
那是种瘾
It's an addiction.
我了解你的感受
I've been where you are.
让我想想我们该怎么做
Let me think about where we go from here.
不  必须今晚行动  她明天就要
No, it has to be tonight. She's getting married
嫁给威尔·德雷克了  她现在分心了
to Will Drake tomorrow. She's distracted.
而且我在她酒里放了
Also, I slipped enough GHB
足够可以放倒一头大象的迷魂药
into her drink to knock out an elephant.
这是个完美的机会
This is the perfect time.
你都安排好了
Oh, you got this all planned.
但...  我无法扣动扳机
But... I can't pull the trigger.
你知道的
You know that.
我欣赏那种
Well, I can appreciate a man
了解自己弱点的男人
who understands his own weakness.
成交吗
Do we have a deal?
来干一杯吧
Let's drink to it.
你知道我为什么想干掉女伯爵
You know why I want to take the Countess down.
你为何这么久还没有复仇
What took you so long to look for revenge, huh?
我怎么知道你可以信任
How do I know I can trust you?
没错
It's true.
20多年前她杀死了我的男人
She killed my man over 20 years ago
把我丢在一边
and tossed me aside.
你知道比心碎还糟的是什么
You know the only thing worse than heartbreak?
孤独
Loneliness.
知道一切永远不会结束
Knowing that it's never going to end.
我非常绝望
So in my despair,
去了世界上唯一一个
I went to the only place in the world
我很确定
where I knew for sure
有爱我的人的地方
there were people who loved me.
洛杉矶  1992年
回到了这个世上
Back to the only man in the world
我唯一曾屈膝的男人身边
that I ever kneeled down for.
你好  爸爸
Hello, daddy.
孩子  我有十年没见过你了
Haven't seen you in ten years, child.
你做了那个整形手术吗
You been doing that plastic surgery?
你哭了  疼吗
You been crying. You hurt?
心里痛
Only on the inside.
真的很痛
Real bad.
我能进去吗
Can I come in?
求你了
Please?
我待了几个月
I stayed for a few months.
妈妈养育我的灵魂  爸爸纠正了我的错
Mama fed my soul, and daddy straightened me right out.
爸爸指导我看清这是什么  那是什么
My daddy pointed his finger at me and told me what was what,
我觉得自己又重新变成了一个小女孩
and I felt like a little girl again.
我安全了
Safe.
爸爸
Daddy.
你没事吧
You all right?
我...
Oh, I...
忘记我说到哪里了
just lost my place there for a moment.
我们之前在说什么
What were we talking about?
亲爱的  这种事总是发生
Honey, it happens all the time now.
凯西  我的钥匙呢
"Cassie, where my keys?
凯西  今天几号
Cassie, what day is it?"
你去看看医生吧  爸爸
You talk to the doctor, daddy?
你妈妈才是病人
Your mama is the sick one.
家里只能有一个病人
Only room for one in the family.
爸爸  明天我开车送你去见萨米医生吧
Daddy, let me drive you over to see Dr. Sammy tomorrow.
我想去的话可以自己开车
I can drive myself if I want to go,
但我不想去
and I don't.
我没事
I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
失去妈妈后  事情就变得更糟了
When we lost mama, things just got worse.
他们结婚60年了
For 60 years, they were married.
没有她  他就再也没有了
without her, his mind just couldn't find a reason
记忆的动力
to hang on.
他开始在自家的街区迷路
He started to get lost in his own neighborhood.
找不到他生活了40年的家
Couldn't find the house that he had lived in for 40 years.
爸爸
Daddy?
看到一个如此优秀的男人沦落至此
To see this great man laid so low.
没关系
It's okay.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be fine.
我见过病毒的威力
I'd seen what the virus had done.
非常难以想象
Miraculous things.
割伤可以迅速愈合
Cuts healed.
骨折在几天内
Broken bones mended
就可以修复
in just a few days' time.
为什么不呢
So why not?
为什么不让它救回我的爸爸
Why couldn't it also bring my daddy back to me?
凯西
Cassie?
凯西  是你吗
Cassie, that you?
但神经并不是割伤
But neurons are not cuts,
生病的大脑也不是断了的骨头
and a diseased brain is not a broken bone.
病毒所做的
All the virus had done
是阻止阿兹海默症的加重
was stop the alzheimer's progression.
妈妈已经走了  爸爸
Mama's gone, daddy.
你知道的
You know that.
你是谁
Who are you?
是我呀  爸爸
It's me, daddy.
我是你的女儿
Your daughter.
他无法自己去找新鲜的血液
He was in no condition to hunt for himself
甚至也不明白他变成了什么样子
or to even understand what he had become.
所以我来照顾他
So I took care of him.
我杀人给他带血液回来
I brought him back blood from my kills.
我还抱着希望  他情况没有恶化
I held out hope that since he wasn't getting any worse,
或许会慢慢好起来
maybe he'd get better.
但他没有好起来
But he didn't get any better.
他一直如此
He just stayed the same.
我们都没有变
We both did.
就这样过了20年
For 20 years.
爸爸  爸爸
Daddy?! Daddy!
爸爸
Daddy.
我不忍心让他这样活着
I couldn't let him live like that,
像被包裹在琥珀里
frozen in amber.
所以我给他吃镇静剂让他平静
So I gave him a xanax to make him calm.
他去世以后
Once he was gone,
我才意识到原来自己也和他一样
I realized that I was frozen in amber, too.
和爸爸在一起的几十年就好像短短20分钟
Decades with my father went by like 20 minutes.
我忘记了一切
I forgot everything.
什么都感觉不到
Felt nothing.
但是这些年中
But a lot of things happened
周边的世界发生了很大的变化
in the world around me in those years.
互联网  该死的葫芦网
The internet. Goddamn hulu.
我以前拍的电影可以免费观看
My old movies streaming for free.
有没有搞错
For free?
又有人开始在街上认出我来
Folks started to recognize me again on the street.
我开始记起很多事
I started remembering.
所有
All of it.
我曾经拥有的  被夺走的
What I had, what had been taken from me,
她对我做的一切
and what she had done to me.
我父亲虽然死了
My daddy's body died,
但我从他身边汲取的能力依旧伴随着我
but the strength I took from his breath stayed with me.
我要用尽这一切
And I am going to use all of it
来毁掉她
to ruin that woman.
敬复仇
To revenge.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
记得我吗  麦克斯
Remember me, Max?
我是劳医生
I'm Dr. Lowe.
我们上次在医院见过
Last time we saw each other was at the hospital.
你因麻疹而奄奄一息
You were dying from measles.
我给你输了血才救活你
I saved you by giving you my blood.
-太好了  谢谢  -这些孩子是谁
- Cool. Thanks. - Who are these other kids?
是我班上的
They're from my class.
都喝了我的血
They drank my blood.
现在我们是同类
Now we're all alike.
你真的是医生吗
Are you really a doctor?
我们不舒服
We don't feel good.
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
你不需要医生
You don't need a doctor.
你得喝血
You have to drink the blood.
这样你就会好一点
That's how you get better.
他是新鲜的  玛德琳
He's a fresh one, Madeline.
不像那些流浪汉一样
Not like the homeless guy.
他的血味道很好
He tastes good.
是你们杀死了那个流浪汉
You killed the homeless man?
新闻上都是的
It's all over the news.
你们不能再这样了  警察会发现你们的
You can't keep doing this. The police are gonna find you.
我告诉过你们了
I told you guys.
这样做不对
This is wrong.
我不想再杀人了
I don't want to kill anymore.
他们逼我杀了我爸妈
They made me kill my parents.
我们都把爸妈吃了
We ate all our parents.
所以才没有人来找我们
That's why nobody's looking for us.
我想妈妈了
I miss my mom.
玛德琳
Madeline,
已经四天了
it's been, like, four days.
你的疹子又出现了  你必须喝血
Your spots are coming back. You have to drink.
大家都是
All of you.
不
No.
你发烧了
You're burning up.
听着  就该甩掉他们
Listen, we should just off them.
这些得病的
All the sickies.
他们还活着的唯一原因
The only reason they're alive is
就是你喜欢玛德琳
because you have a crush on Madeline.
闭嘴  吉米
Shut up, Jimmy.
伙计  别叫我真名
Dude, don't use my real name.
现在她知道我的身份了
Now she knows who I am.
很快人人都会知道你是谁了
Pretty soon everybody's gonna know who you are.
你们杀了一个送披萨的
You killed the pizza delivery guy.
半小时之内人们就会发现他失踪了
In about 30 minutes, they're gonna know he went missing.
他们有你们的地址
They have your address.
警察会直奔此地的
The cops are gonna come right here to the house.
和我一起去科泰兹酒店吧
Come with me, all of you, to the Hotel Cortez.
那里有我们的同类
There are people there like us.
他们知道该如何处理
They'll know how to fix this.
对  大人对我们的指手画脚正是我们需要的
Right. Cause that's what we need-- adults telling us what to do.
见鬼去吧
Screw that.
听着  我们还有半小时的时间
Listen, we have half an hour.
我们可以离开
We can get out of here.
但  她呢
It's just... what about her?
规矩是你定的  麦克斯
You made the rule, Max.
没人可以活着离开我们
Nobody leaves us alive.
不
No!
是她造就的我们
She made us.
她可以离开
She can leave.
和我一起去旅馆吧
Come with me to the hotel.
我说了  走
I said leave!
我可以帮你们
I can help you!
好吧  我们走
Fine. We're leaving.
你去和警察解释吧
You explain it to the cops.
她还没醒
She's still out.
也许根本不会有感觉
She probably won't feel anything.
那太糟了
That's too bad.
我唯一的遗憾
My only regret
就是她根本不知道怎么死的
is that she won't know what's coming
也不知道是谁送她上的路
and who's giving it to her.
你要怎么做
What are you going to do?
我会一刀刺进她的心脏
I'm gonna stab her in the heart and then
再割下她的头
cut off her head.
保证她死得透透的
Make sure she stays dead.
那我要干什么
What do you want me to do?
看着就好
Watch.
看看有胆子的人是怎么把这事了了的
See how someone with cojones finishes the job.
够胆了吗
‭Ballsy enough for you?
多诺万  我不明白
Donovan, I don't understand this.
用她做诱饵吗
We're using her as bait?
她同意了吗
Did she agree to this?
这是备用计划吗
Is this plan "B"?
没有备用计划
There is no plan "B."
那我们要怎么做
Well, then, what are we doing?
这些摄像机是干什么的
What are all these cameras for?
我们把仇家都引过来  关到这里
We are collecting our enemies and putting them in here.
好好欣赏他们
We're gonna hate-watch.
我们的敌人
Our enemies?
你是说她的敌人吧
You mean her enemies, don't you?
她的敌人就是我的敌人
Her enemies are my enemies.
该死
Aw, shit.
天啊  多诺万
God, Donovan.
她爱我  艾芮斯
She loves me, Iris.
我也将永远爱她
And I never stopped loving her.
所有反对我们的人最后的下场就是这样
Anyone who's against us is gonna end up in here,
所以你还是别费口舌了
so just keep that in mind.
你和那贱人没有未来的
There is no us with that bitch.
她心里只有自己
It's just her and surviving
她想什么时候弄死你就什么时候弄死你
until she decides it's time for you to die!
我们三人联手
The three of us, together--
是打败她的唯一办法
it's the only chance we have to destroy her.
你真以为我们三个是搭档吗
Did you really think the three of us could ever be partners?
那你为什么要救我
Well, then, why did you save me?
我心软了
I was weak.
就该让你死掉的
I should have let you die.
不
No.
会死的是你  孩子
You're the one who's gonna die, son.
你该听妈妈的话
You should listen to your mama.
她说得没错
She's right.
闭嘴
Shut up.
给我闭嘴
Shut up!
走吧
Go.
你以为自己是她的唯一吗
You think you're her one and only?
你就是这么想的吧  她早已抛下你
That's what you think? She has already moved on
另寻新欢了  绝对的
to the next one; you can count on it.
如果你还不明白
You don't know that,
那你更是一个蠢到家的小白脸了
then you're more dumb than you are pretty.
不过你还真是帅
And you are very pretty.
我已经不了解这个世界了
It is a world I no longer recognize
这个世界也已经不认识我了
and which no longer recognizes me.
不为人所知是福分  亲爱的
Anonymity is your friend, my love.
为了生存  我们必须谨慎
To survive, we must be cunning
更要隐姓埋名
and stick to the shadows.
娜塔莎不这么认为
Natacha does not see it that way.
她为未来世界迷住了
She has been drawn in by the future.
这个现代社会蛊惑了她
This modern world speaks to her.
你给了她那张黑色的
I haven't even seen her
塑料卡片后  我还没有见过她
since you gave her that black plastic card.
她嘴里就只有购物和打车软件了
She speaks of nothing but shopping and... Uber.
她花了我好多钱
She's costing me a fortune.
但也是值得的
But it's worth it, I'll admit.
这样一来  我就能和你独处了
I did it so I could have you all to myself.
我以为你是爱娜塔莎的
But I thought you loved Natacha.
我爱她是因为你爱她
I loved her because you did.
也因为当年我还年少  缺乏自信
And because I was young and lacking in self-confidence.
我以为对你来说  我还不够女人
I thought I wasn't woman enough for you.
小美人
Bellissima...
在我们俩眼中  你都足够女人味
you are woman enough for the both of us.
从你眼中我能看到逝去世界的一些东西
When I look at you, I see something of my vanished world.
你可以重新拥有那个世界
We can have that world again.
不
No.
已经不存在了
It is lost.
这个世界已经容不下魔法了
There is no place for enchantment anymore.
我们可以建造一片净土
We can make a place.
重新创造一个
We can create one.
过去的一百年里
God knows I've been trying
我一直在努力重造你
to recreate you for the last century.
那些苍白的复制品来了又去  马上就不存在了
A series of pale imitations, gone, or soon to be.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我在为我们清理道路
I've been clearing the way for us.
我们很快就能重新拥有曾经失去的了
We are so close to recapturing what we once lost.
我很快就能继承到一大笔钱
I'm about to come into a great deal of money.
我们可以用这笔钱把科泰兹
We can use it to turn the Cortez
打造成一个对抗现代社会的堡垒
into a fortress against the modern world.
我比你还讨厌现在这个世界
A world I hate even more than you.
那娜塔莎呢
And what of Natacha?
如果她出了什么意外
If something were to happen to her...
你还活得下去吗
could you go on?
还有你来慰藉我的心
I would have you to comfort me.
小老鼠
Little mouse!
你说得一点没错
You were so right.
脏兮兮的贝弗利山现在太绚丽了
It's astounding what's become of dusty Beverly Hills.
商店一家连一家
Shops, shops and more shops.
鲁迪  你不会相信我看到了什么
Rudy, you won't believe what I found.
以你命名的商店  瓦伦蒂诺[华伦天奴]
A store with your name on it-- "Valentino."
零售店都还是不错的  不过真正的好衣服嘛
Retail's all well and good, but for the true couture,
还得去我那儿
you have to come to my place.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
我永远都不会再踏进科泰兹了
I'm never stepping foot in the Cortez again.
詹姆斯·马奇已经死了  你们绝对安全
James March is long dead. You're perfectly safe.
我一会儿派车来接你们
I'll have a car come pick you up later.
鲁迪  你没被邀请呢
Oh, and, Rudy, you're not invited.
今晚是女生之夜
It's just us girls tonight.
如果在场有任何人
If anyone present knows any reason
有反对这对男女结为夫妻的理由
why this man and this woman should not be joined in marriage,
请现在说出  此后将永不得再说
speak now or forever hold your peace.
我有话
Yeah.
因为她是个贱人
Because she's a bitch
没有良心和慈悲心
with no conscience, no mercy,
更没有灵魂
no soul.
丽兹
Oh, Liz.
别理她  她喝多了
Ignore her. She drinks.
但法律要求有见证人
But the law requires a witness.
我看得够多的了
And I've witnessed plenty.
请继续吧
Please proceed.
现在我宣布你们正式结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
我的丈夫  我的家
My men, my family.
终于成为威尔·德雷克夫人  我太高兴了
I am so happy to finally be Mrs. Will Drake.
爸爸  我能上楼去了吗
Dad, can I go upstairs now?
当然可以  我也要上楼
Of course you may, and I am going to go upstairs
脱下你为我设计的这身漂亮的礼服
and change out of this beautiful gown you've made me
换一身旅行装
and put on my traveling clothes.
确定不用先喝一杯庆祝一下吗
You sure you don't want to have a drink to celebrate first?
蜜月就是为了庆祝啊
That's what the honeymoon is for.
我希望马上就开始
I'd like to get that started.
好吧  那我得先来一杯
All right, well, I think I'm going to.
夫人我找不到发对的理由  吧台是你的了
Your wife finds no reason to object, and you own the bar.
亲爱的丽兹
My darling Liz,
这是给你的
these are for you
我真心希望有一天你能找到真爱
With my genuine hope that you someday find true love.
谁也不知道真爱之人何时会出现
One never knows when it may appear.
对  敬科泰兹的领袖
Ah, yes! A toast to the guide of Cortez.
也有人称她为  科泰兹的新娘
Or as some folks called her, the bride of Cortez.
我姓马奇  常住人士
March is the name. Longtime resident.
叫我詹姆斯就好
Call me James.
能一起吗
Mind if I join you?
我想你一定是有喜事要庆祝吧
I understand, uh, congratulations are in order.
确实如此  詹姆斯
They are indeed, James.
为你的好运干一杯如何
Let's toast to your good fortune, hmm?
你这儿有雅邑白兰地吗
I wouldn't suppose you have an armagnac?
我猜你有吧
I, uh, suspect you do.
敬将去征服的新世界
Here's to new worlds to conquer.
干杯
I will drink to that.
好
Ah, yes.
我们都被生命中的女人所牵引  是不是
We are led by the women in our lives, are we not?
你认识女伯爵
You know the Countess?
算是熟人吧
Acquainted, yes.
我从没想过我会结婚
I never thought I was the marrying kind,
现在我得叫那个女人妻子了
and now I get to call that woman my wife.
恭喜你们这对新人啊
Felicitations to the happy couple.
我真得夸夸你
I must commend you.
混合家庭绝对是开明之举
A blended family is terribly progressive.
我很幸运  她爱我的儿子
I'm very lucky. She loves my son very much.
我...
I, uh...
说的不是你儿子
wasn't referring to your son.
一开始我怀疑
Initially, I had my doubts
那孩子是我的亲骨肉
the child was of my own flesh and blood.
但他并没有遗传到马奇家的任何特性
You see, he doesn't bear any of the distinctive March features.
完美的下巴  坚韧而富有穿透力的眼睛
Diamond jaw, strong, piercing eyes.
戏剧性的天赋
A flair for the dramatic.
他性格内敛
He has quite a delicate temperament,
你马上就会看到了
as you'll get to know.
除了他喝奶的时候
Except when he's feeding.
从那一点看  他绝对遗传了他母亲
In that regard, he most certainly takes after his mother.
见鬼
‭Holy shit!
那是什么东西
What the hell is that thing?
想想看  我会好好爱你儿子  抚养他长大的
And to think, I was prepared to love and raise your son.
这是怎么回事
What is going on?
这是什么  恶作剧吗
What is this-- some, some sort of prank?
那东西不可能是你儿子
That thing can't be yours.
他都不像是人类
It doesn't even look human!
我本想在巴黎把你杀了的
I thought to kill you in Paris,
但我无法忍受和一个
but I could never stomach traveling with someone
这样说我孩子坏话的男人一起出行的
who said such hateful things about my child.
我一定会让你
I am going to make sure you suffer
生不如死
immensely.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我们这是在哪儿  你是谁
Where the hell are we? Who are you?
她的受害者之一
One of her victims.
和你一样
Just like you.
这一定是疯了
This... this is insane.
不是真的
This can't be real.
你马上就会知道有多真实了
You're about to find out just how real it is,
等他们回到这儿
when they come back down here
把你钉上到那上面
and stick you in that other one.
求你了  救我出去
Please... get me out of this.
求你了
Please!
后面有一个把手
There's a handle in the back.
找到了
Yeah.
好了
All right.
好了  不会有事的
All right, it's gonna be okay. ‭
一定有办法出去的
There's got to be a way out of here.
有人吗
Hello?!
Is anybody there?!
救命
Help!
放我们出去
Let us out of here!
救命
Help!
天啊  我觉得是隔音的
Jesus, I think it's soundproof.
没人知道我们在这儿
No one even knows we're here.
我们会饿死的
We'll starve.
我不会
I won't.